We're now ready to use some of the similarity matrix that we've seen
现在我们可以使用之前学习的相似性矩阵
to better understand how users and items are related to one another.
更好地了解用户或项目相互之间的关系了
That's the point of collaborative filtering is to look
这就是协同过滤的作用
at how users or items might be correlated in
即查看用户或项目以不同的方式相互有何关系
different ways and then learn from that to better make
然后利用这些相关性
recommendations for new users or users who might have similar tastes.
更好地向新用户或有相似品位的用户推荐内容
With that, this notebook,
在此 notebook 中
we're going to get started.
我们将开始...
It looks like the progress bar doesn't exist.
似乎进度条没出现
So, we'll need to pip install
先用 pip install 命令安装进度条
that, free go back.
然后再返回 notebook
It looks like everything's working now.
现在一切正常了
So, the first thing that they want to do is just give us
首先我们来看看
a reminder of the reviews DataFrame that we're going to be working with.
我们将使用的 reviews DataFrame
So, it has the user ID,
它有一个 user_id 列
the movie ID, and the rating.
movie_id 列和 rating 列
A lot of times, when you're making recommendations,
很多时候 在做出推荐时
this is about all the information that you're given,
我们只有这些信息
is a user ID, and movie ID, and our rating,
即用户 ID、电影 ID 和评分
or even a user ID, a movie ID,
或者是用户 ID、电影 ID
or some item ID,
或某种项目 ID
and then whether or not that user has interacted with the item.
然后是用户是否与该项目互动的信息
So, there might be like a one here if they interacted with each other,
可能是 1 表示互动了
or zero if they haven't. Something like that.
或 0 表示没有互动类似于这样的信息
So, the main way that we're going to work
处理这种数据的主要方式是
with this data is frequently in what is known as a User-Item matrix.
创建用户-项目矩阵
If you go to the link here,
你可以点击这个链接
it shows you a way to do this.
了解如何解决内存错误
I originally tried to use a pivot table to do it,
我一开始尝试使用数据透视表
but I got a memory error.
但是遇到了内存错误
That was a reoccurring problem in working with this dataset and
在使用此数据集时经常出现该错误
multiple cases was that I continued to
当我尝试采用不同的方式时
get memory errors when I tried to do things in different ways.
多次遇到了内存错误
So, you'll notice as we go through making recommendations,
所以在介绍创建推荐系统的步骤时
we'll frequently do it on a subset of the data and then you can imagine
我们将经常使用该数据的子集
extending the ideas to larger datasets or even to the full dataset here.
你可以将这些步骤扩展到更大的数据集上 甚至是整个数据集
So, if you go to the link,
点击链接后 你会发现
it shows that you can actually take this user item's DataFrame,
我们可以使用这个 user_items DataFrame 创建一个矩阵
and create something with users or user IDs on the rows and
每行存储的是用户或用户 ID
movie IDs on the columns by performing a groupby,
每列存储的是电影 ID
and basically just grouping by the user Id and the movie ID.
我们可以使用 groupby() 按照 user_id 和 movie_id 分组
Then, what we want to do is pull
然后 我们可以提取评分
the rating and then we could pull the min-max or whatever,
我们可以提取最小值、最大值或其他值
it really doesn't matter because we just need the value itself.
这不重要 因为我们只需要值本身
So, we pull the rating column.
我们提取出 rating 列
We could pull anything.
然后提取任何类型的值
This could be the mean or the min or the max because when we grouped by these two things,
可以是均值、最小值或最大值
there's only one existing rating for each of those.
因为如果按这两项分组 每项只有一个评分
Then, there's this thing called an unstack,
然后使用 unstack() 方法
which is useful because that's what's going to
它很有用
create the rows and columns the way that we want them to.
因为它可以按照我们想要的方式创建行和列
But once that's done running,
运行完毕后
we can check that our matrix matches the solution and Jimmy Fallon tells us that it does.
我们检查下矩阵是否与解答中的矩阵一致 这个 Jimmy Fallon 动图表明的确一致